# Federico Rossi | Software Engineer

reddyfede@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a Software Engineer with a background and work experience in Industrial Engineering.

In my previous job I worked closely with software suppliers doing Business Analysis and Quality Assurance to implement new software for the factory.

This gave me the opportunity to experience the full life cycle of a software and helped me to always be aware of clients' needs.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Python | SQL | EJS

Libraries and Framework: Node.js | React.js | Express.js | Django | Bootstrap | Tailwind

Databases: PostgreSQL | MongoDB

Utilities: Git | Github | CLI

Various: Project Management | Business Analysis | Quality Assurance

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Digital Transformation Manager**

Sarezzo, Italy

Ottoman | Turnery | Industrial Engineering

2020 - 2023

- Managed new projects for the company computerization and automation:
  - Business Analysis to evaluate company needs, definition of specifications for software supplier;
    - Quality Assurance and testing of the new software before deployment;
    - Training and support for the staff regarding the new software.
- Scheduled the production orders for 44 production machines, assigned daily tasks to 10 operators.
- Managed and maintained the Quality Control System.
- Maintained the existing IT infrastructure:
  - Managed the customization and set up of new MES Software packages:
  - Defined procedures for the use of company software;
  - First level IT support.

#### **Technical Department**

Italy

OFAR, Franchini Acciai | Forge | Industrial Engineering

2018 - 2020

- Analyzed client orders and specifications to ensure product feasibility.
- Engineered production cycle based on client requirements.
- Created and managed the status of production orders.

## **EDUCATION**

## **General Assembly**

Online

Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp

July 2023 - October 2023

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 12-weeks, 480+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

## Universitá degli studi eCampus

Italy

Bachelor Degree in Management Engineering

2022

## **CODING PROJECTS**

**Task flow** | TaskFlow is an application to manage your team work. Team Leader can create tasks and assign them to team members based on their weekly availability. Team members can view their daily tasks on a gantt chart. Roles: Planning, UI Design, Frontend, Backend | 10 days project | Live | Github

- Planning and task management with Trello, ERD and Concept Design with Figma.
- Extra Features: interactive gantt to display the daily tasks.
- Tech used: Frontend: React, Styled-Components; Backend: Django; DB: PostgreSQL

**Event.ly** | Event.ly is a map-based MERN application for finding and creating events to connect with people in your local community. Created as a 10 days pair programming project at GA Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp. Roles: Planning, UI Design, Frontend, Backend | 10 days project | Live | Github

- Planning and task management with Trello, ERD and Concept Design with Figma.
- Created application with a mobile-first approach and styled using the CSS framework Tailwind.
- Made RESTful API calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all CRUD operations, tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Extra Features: integration with Leaflet map, integration with 0Auth for secure user authentication, integration with Unsplash API to retrieve custom pictures, integration with Bing Maps API for reverse geocoding.
- Tech used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, Tailwind.

**Little Italy Pizza** | Little Italy Pizza is a MEN stack web application for a fictitious pizza shop. Created as a weeklong pair programming project at GA Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp.

Roles: Planning, UI Design, Frontend, Backend | Week-long project | Live | Github

- Extra Features: Animation with CSS framework Bootstrap.
- Tech used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Bootstrap

## **SPOKEN LANGUAGES**

Italian | English

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

Founding memberGhedi, ItalyPerSampre2014-2020

Charity-event planning in memory of our friend Sam.

EducatorGhedi, ItalyOratorio San Giovanni Bosco2014-2017

Worked with a class of teenagers, creating activities and weekly meetings.